Preliminary Inventory to the George Davis Herron Papers, 1916-1927
Hoover Institution Archives
- BOUND VOLUMES (on shelf)
  - Volume VII. Bulgaria
    - Herron to Mr. Gueschoff. Expressing regret at departure; good impressions of Italy; tribute to Mr. Gueschoff's service in Switzerland; profound grief of failure towards Bulgaria; reaction in America, 1920 May 7 (Item LXXXIX)
    - Same. Introducing Mr. Paul Mowrer; his mission to Eastern Europe, 1920 May 10 (Item XC)
    - Mr. Gueschoff to Herron. Departure for Bulgaria; note of goodbye, 1920 June 10 (Item XCI)
    - Anonymous to Herron. Warning against Bulgarian agents; Caranguiloff; Dr. Stefanoff. In French, 1920 June 14 (Item XCII)
    - Mr. Gueschoff to Herron. Acknowledging "Cashiers Idéalistes"; Mr. Paul Mowrer; desire to join staff of Chicago Daily News; good Bulgarian harvest; occupation by Greeks of Turkish Thrace; Bulgarians working hard, 1920 July 10 (Item XCIII)
    - Herron to Mr. Gueschoff. Acknowledging above; Mahomedan world uniting against France and England; Polish situation; Bolsheviks; Bulgaria should exercise restraining influence over Albania; Mr. Mowrer; departure for Ragaz, 1920 July 26 (Item XCIV)
    - Mr. Shipkoff to Herron. Various views; desire to go to America but passport denied; request for help, 1920 August 12 (Item XCV)
      The following documents, containing references to Bulgaria, are in ROUMANIA, which see:
      - Document I: 1918 May 25
      - Document I-A: 1918 May 25
      - Document VI: 1919 August 14
      - Document VII: 1919 August 15
      - Document X: 1919 August 25
      - Document XI: 1919 August 25
      - Document XVIII: 1919 September 6
      - Document XXIII: 1919 October 15
      - Document XXIV: 1919 October 19
      - Document XXV-A: 1919 October 28
      - Document XXVI: 1919 October 29
      - Document XXVII: 1919 November 12
      - Document XXX: 1920 January 6
  - Volume VIII. Macedonia
    - Dr. A. Kotzareff to Herron. Asking for interview. In French, 1919 May 15 (Item I)
    - Same and M. Bl. Boyadjieff, 1919 May 23 (Item II)
    - Same to The President, 1919 May 23 (Item II A)
    - Same. Letter giving various particulars towards United States' protectorate over independent Macedonia (Item II B)
    - Herron to Mr. Boyadjieff. Giving assurance that appeal has been forwarded to The President, 1919 May 26 (Item III)
    - Herron to Dr. Kotzareff. Giving assurance of sympathetic interest in Macedonian question, 1919 May 26 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Colonel House and Sir William Tyrrell. Specifying Macedonian plea; their special refusal to be annexed to Yougo-Slavia, 1919 May 26 (Item V)
    - Dr. Kotzareff and M. Bl. Boyadjieff to Herron. Enclosing appeal "Pro Macedonia." In French, 1919 June 30 (Item VI)
    - Same. Above appeal, in French, 1919 May 30 (Item VI A)
    - Mr. Whitney Shepardson to Herron. Acknowledging Document V for Colonel House, 1919 July 1 (Item VII)
    - Ing. V.L. Stkonahow and Mr. Bl. Boyadjieff to Herron. Expressing gratitude for Herron's interest in Macedonian question; requesting interview. In French, 1919 July 17 (Item VIII)
    - Mr. Boyadjieff to Mrs. Herron. Request for Herron to go to Paris to plead Macedonian cause; Dr. Kotzareff replaced by Professor Stephanove on staff of Conseil Général, 1919 August 8 (Item IX)
    - Professor Stephanove and Mr. Boyadjieff to Herron for transmission to The President, 1919 August 12 (Item X)
    - Herron to Macedonian Council. Suggesting interview, 1919 August 13 (Item XI)
    - Professor Stephanove to Herron. Arranging for interview, 1919 August 14 (Item XII)
    - Herron to Minister Stovall, 1919 August 16 (Item XIII)
    - Herron to Colonel House. Seeking advice as to accepting request of Macedonians to go to Paris to plead their cause, 1919 August 16 (Item XIV)
    - Colonel House to Herron. Question will be discussed with Mr. Polk, 1919 August 23 (Item XV)
    - Professor Stephanove to Herron. Acknowledging article in "La Semaine Littéraire"; petition to Peace Conference published in "London Times"; change of address, 1919 August 25 (Item XVI)
    - Herron to Professor Stephanove. Request to go to Paris, 1919 August 26 (Item XVII)
    - Mr. Stephanove to Herron. Extract from letter of Mr. Paul Scott Mowrer on just peace in the Balkans, 1919 August 28 (Item XVIII)
    - Minister Stovall to Herron. Replying to letter of 16th; Peace Mission in Paris do not encourage Herron to accept Macedonian invitation, 1919 August 28 (Item XIX)
    - Herron to Mr. Cazenove. Giving general Macedonian situation; Balkan matters in the hands of Mr. Venizelos; giving permission for transmission, 1919 August 28 (Item XX)
    - Herron to Minister Stovall. Acknowledging Document XIX, 1919 August 29 (Item XXI)
    - Herron to Professor Stephanove. Conveying Document XIX; Mr. Venizelos and Yougo-Slavs to the fore in Paris; will try to enlist Mr. Balfour's interest, 1919 August 29 (Item XXII)
    - Professor Stephanove to Herron, 1919 September 1 (Item XXIII)
    - Professor Stephanove to Herron. Forcible conscription in Macedonia, 1919 September 8 (Item XXIV)
    - Herron to Professor Stephanove. Return of Colonel House to Paris, in spite of disagreements, 1919 September 13 (Item XXV)
    - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 September 13 (Item XXVI)
    - Mr. S. Bonsal to Herron. Acknowledging above letter for Colonel House; letter from Professor Stephanove, 1919 September 18 (Item XXVII)
    - Professor Stephanove and Mr. Boyadjieff to Herron. Elation over Colonel House's attitude; request for article to be published in "L'Indépendance Macédonienne," 1919 October 3 (Item XXVIII)
    - Mr. Bonsal to Professor Stephanove. Protest against recruitment of soldiers in Macedonia, 1919 September 18 (Item XXVIII A)
    - Herron to Professor Stephanove. Impossibility to write article; belief in free Macedonia as corner stone of Balkan Federation, 1919 October 7 (Item XXIX)
    - Herron to Professor Stephanove. Article concerning Thrace and Macedonia; suggestion to Mr. Shipkoff for pamphlet; collaboration of Professor Micheff, 1919 October 17 (Item XXX)
    - Professor Stephanove to Herron. Acknowledging above; personal letter to Mr. Polk; article has been sent to America and England; enclosing criticism on his book, 1919 October 24 (Item XXXI)
    - Enclosure; literary criticism in "The London Times," 1919 September 25 (Item XXXI A)
    - Professor Stephanove to Herron. Pamphlet on "Question of Thrace"; preparations for near departure, 1919 November 7 (Item XXXII)
    - Professor Stephanove to Herron. Last words from station of Lausanne, 1919 November 10 (Item XXXIII)
    - Same. Independent action in Switzerland; most Macedonians in agreement; particulars of journey to Sofia, 1919 December 29 (Item XXXIV)
    - Herron to Professor Stephanove, 1920 January 15 (Item XXXV)
    - Professor Stephanove to Herron. Acknowledging above; welcome to Herron if he arrives in Sofia, 1920 February 8 (Item XXXVI)
    - Herron to Professor Stephanove. Breakdown of health; administrative anarchy in America; "The Peace of Paris and the Youth of Europe," 1920 February 18 (Item XXXVII)
    - Professor Stephanove to Herron, 1920 April 1 (Item XXXVIII)
    - Professor Stephanove to Herron, 1920 April 10 (Item XXXIX)
    - Herron to Professor Stephanove, 1920 April 29 (Item XL)
    - Professor Stephanove to Herron. Return to Sofia; Mr. Karandjsuloff; acknowledging latest books, 1920 August 17 (Item XLI)
  - Volume IX. Roumania
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 May 25 (Item I)
    - Same (Item I A)
    - Dr. N.P. Commène to Herron. Request for article for "La Roumanie." In French, 1918 November 21 (Item II)
    - Same. Telegram - interview, 1918 December 22 (Item III)
    - Report concerning the commission of the Protestant Churches of Hungary in Geneva and their presentation of the Roumanian situation, 1919 January 10. Transferred to HUNGARY, Document XXXIII (Item IV)
    - Dr. Commène to Herron. Desire to publish interview with Herron. In French, 1919 August 13 (Item V)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène, 1919 August 14 (Item VI)
    - Same. Interview with Mr. Shipkoff; Roumania should agree with Bulgaria for demand of Macedonian independence, 1919 August 15 (Item VII)
    - Same. Telegram - interview, 1919 August 21 (Item VIII)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène and Mr. Schiopul, for the King of Roumania, 1919 August 22 (Item IX)
    - Same. French translation of above (Item IX A)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène. Telegram - interview with Mr. Gueshoff, 1919 August 25 (Item X)
    - Same, 1919 August 25 (Item XI)
    - Same. Enclosing copy of article for American syndicate, 1919 August 26 (Item XII)
    - Article by Herron. "The New Roumania" published in "New Europe" and "The New York Times," undated (Item XII A)
    - Signor R. Prunal to Herron. Transmitting telegram. In Italian, 1919 August 26 (Item XIII)
    - Favorable attitude of Italian press towards Roumanian Cause; various papers mentioned. In Italian (Item XIII A)
    - Mr. J. Schiopul to Herron. Conveying Mr. Commène's thanks for article on Roumania; enclosing other article, 1919 August 27 (Item XIV)
    - Herron to Mr. Schiopul. Forwarding his admirable letter for publication, 1919 August 28 (Item XV)
    - Herron to Marquis Paulucci. Requesting interview, 1919 August 30 (Item XVI)
    - Herron to Count Sforza, 1919 August (approximately) (Item XVI A)
    - Herron to Mr. Commène. Rapprochement between Roumania and her neighbors; failure of Peace Conference. In French, 1919 September 4 (Item XVII)
    - Statement presented to British Foreign Office, 1919 September 6 (Item XVIII)
    - Mr. Schiopul to Herron. Request to publish letter for Cluj; no news from Dr. Commène; arrival of new minister, 1919 September 16 (Item XIX)
    - Signed by John Creco, 1919 September 5 (Item XIX A)
    - Herron to Mr. Commène. Enclosing various letters, 1919 September 17 (Item XX)
    - Herron to Mr. Schiopul. Acknowledging letter of Mr. Greco; sending same to Colonel House, 1919 September 18 (Item XXI)
    - Mr. Schiopul to Herron. Letter from Dr. Commène; particulars regarding Mr. Greco, 1919 September 26 (Item XXII)
    - Herron to Colonel Rosetti, 1919 October 14 (Item XXII-bis)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène, 1919 October 15. In French (Item XXIII)
    - Dr. Commène to Herron, 1919 October 19 (Item XXIV)
    - Herron to Mr. Schiopul. Request to forward enclosure to Dr. Commène, 1919 October 28 (Item XXV)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène, 1919 October 28 (Item XXV A)
    - Same. Suggesting Professor Lammasch, Dr. Muehlon and Professor Nippold or Professor Pittard for question of quadrilateral Doubridja, 1919 October 29 (Item XXVI)
    - Same. Departure of Bulgarians from Switzerland and Paris; insisting upon Roumanian initiative. In French, 1919 November 12 (Item XXVII)
    - Dr. Commène to Herron, 1919 December 20 (Item XXVIII)
    - Constantin Noe to Dr. Commène, 1920 January 4 (Item XXIX)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène. Meeting to organize League of Small Nations; Roumania should be represented; Mr. Chavichvily; Mr. Gueschoff, 1920 January 6 (Item XXX)
    - Same, 1920 January 13 (Item XXXI)
    - Herron to Mr. Tumulty, 1920 January 14 (Item XXXII)
    - Mr. Schiopul to Herron, 1920 January 14 (Item XXXII A)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell. Same, enclosing above (Item XXXII B)
    - To Colonel House (Item XXXII C)
    - To Mr. R.W. Seton-Watson (Item XXXII D)
    - To Mr. Frank A. Vanderlip (Item XXXII E)
    - To Mr. C.W. Barron (Item XXXII F)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène. Manuscript to Mr. Fazy; its publication; general peace and relations of Great Powers and enemy countries. In French, 1920 January 15 (Item XXXIII)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène. Interview with Mr. S.J. Jennings of "The London Daily News," 1920 January 16 (Item XXXIV)
    - Herron to same as Document XXXIII B. Enclosing third letter from Roumania, 1920 January 20 (Item XXXV)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène. Enclosing letter to King Ferdinand; interview with Mr. Schiopul. In French, 1920 January 20 (Item XXXVI)
    - Herron to The King of Roumania, 1920 January 20 (Item XXXVI A)
    - Herron to Minister Derussi. Same as above, in French, 1920 January 21 (Item XXXVII)
    - Herron to Mr. Tumulty. Enclosing copy of Document XXXVI A, 1920 January 22 (Item XXXVIII)
    - Herron to Mr. Schiopul. Enclosing copy of letter to Mr. Barron, 1920 January 23 (Item XXXIX)
    - Mr. Tumulty to Herron. Acknowledging Document XXXVIII, 1920 February 10 (Item XL)
    - Herron to Mr. Schiopul. Enclosing letter to Dr. Commène; Roumania's opportunity, 1920 March 23 (Item XLI)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène, 1920 March 23 (Item XLI A)
    - Herron to Count Sforza. Enclosing various Roumanian memoranda, 1920 April 19 (Item XLII)
    - Herron to Mr. Fazy. Enclosing note on Bessarabia and one for Dr. Commène; Mr. Schiopul, 1920 April 26 (Item XLIII)
    - Herron to Mr. Fazy, 1920 April 26 (Item XLIII A)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène. Introducing Mr. Paul Mowrer, in French, 1920 May 10 (Item XLIV)
  - Volume IX. Roumania. The Banat
    - Herron to Dr. Commène, 1919 May 16 (Item I)
    - Dr. Commène to Herron, 1919 May 19 (Item II)
    - Page 17 (Item II A to Document II A)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène, 1919 May 20 (Item III)
    - Herron to The President. Conveying entire question of The Banat, with English preface to confidential documents, 1919 May 20 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell. Same as above for Mr. Balfour (Item IV B)
    - Herron to Dr. E.J. Dillon. Same as above (Item IV C)
    - Herron to Marquis Paulucci. Enclosing above documents; Italy's opportunity for courageous initiative; hegemony of international financiers, 1919 May 26 (Item V)
    - Herron to Dr. Commène. Suggesting publication of Bela Khun's negotiations in The Banat, in view of relations between Roumania and the bolshevist government of Hungary. In French, 1919 June 12 (Item VI)
    - Dr. Commène to Herron. Telegram, in French. Agreeing to suggestion, which Herron ultimately cancel, 1919 June 13 (Item VII)
    - 1919 June (approximately) (Item VIII)
  - Volume IX. The Near East
    - Greece
      - M. Eustache Mazarachi to Herron. Sending text of unspecified correspondence. In French, undated (Item I)
      - Memorandum furnished to Herron by Prince Christopher and Mr. Streitt, Foreign Minister under King Constantine, 1919 June 20 (Item I A)
      - Herron to Officers of British Foreign Office, 1919 June (approximatel) (Item II)
    - Turkey
      - Herron to the State Department, 1918 December 10 (Item I)
      - Herron to the British Foreign Office, 1918 December 10 (Item I A)
      - Transferred to the League of Nations, Document X (Item II)
      - Transferred to The League of Nations, Document XI (Item III)
      - Transferred to The League of Nations, Document XII (Item IV)
      - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 April 30 (Item V)
    - Armenia
      - Foreword by Professor Edgard Milhaud, 1918 October 21 (Item I)
      - Report by M. Mikael Varandian, 1918 October 21 (Item I A)
      - Herron to The State Department and British Foreign Office, 1918 October 23 (Item II)
      - Herron to The Hon. Pleasant Stovall, 1918 October 26 (Item III)
      - Herron to M. Mikael Varandian, 1918 November 4 (Item IV)
      - Herron to President Wilson, 1918 November 4 (Item V)
      - Monsieur Varandian to Herron, 1918 November 10 (Item VI)
      - Report by M. Varandian, undated (Item VI A)
      - M. Varandian to Herron, 1918 November 13 (Item VII)
      - Herron to Mr. Stovall, 1918 November 14 (Item VIII)
      - Herron to His Excellency Sir Horace Rumbold, Bart., M.V.O., K.C.M.G., 1918 November 14 (Item IX)
      - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 November 15 (Item X)
      - Herron to the British Foreign Office, 1918 November 16 (Item XI)
      - Herron to State Department, 1918 November 16 (Item XII)
      - Sir Horace Rumbold to Herron, 1918 December 7 (Item XIII)
      - Herron to Sir Horace Rumbold, 1918 December 19 (Item XIV)
      - Mr. J.K. Agathon to Herron, 1919 October 3 (Item XV)
      - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 October 3 (Item XVI)
      - Herron to various people, 1919 October 2 (Item XVI A)
      - Herron to Mr. Charles R. Crance, 1919 October 8 (Item XVII)
    - Persia
      - M. Ali Akber to Herron, 1919 October 4 (Item I)
      - M. Ayu-Lama Bey to Herron, 1919 October 4 (Item I A)
      - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 October 4 (Item I B)
    - Egypt
      - Mohamed Faymy, Aly Shamsy, Ismail Labid, Yehya Dardiry to Herron, for President Wilson. Shortly before Peace Conference (Item I)
  - Volume X. Russia
    - Herron to M. Wladimir Victoroff-Toporoff, 1918 April 30 (Item I)
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1918 April 30 (Item II)
    - Report given to Herron by Mme. Hertzka, 1918 July (approximately) (Item III)
    - Madame Olivier to Herron. Telegram. Committee to President Wilson, 1918 September 4 (Item IV)
    - Herron to State Department, 1918 October 27 (Item V)
    - Herron to Mr. Stovall, 1918 November 1 (Item VI)
    - Appeal on behalf of Russian prisoners of war by Dr. N.A. Kossianoff, President of the Russian Red Cross in Berne; perishing from hunger, want and sickness, under most distressing conditions; particulars, immediate help indispensable, from humanitarian and political point of view (Item VI A)
    - Herron to State Department and British Foreign Office, 1918 November 20 (Item VII)
    - Report by Mr. Siegfried Horneffer. Transferred to Germany, Document XCVIII, 1919 January 4 (Item VIII)
    - Colonel House to Herron. Russian situation is being duly considered, 1919 February 16 (Item IX)
    - Monsieur N. Gay to Herron, 1919 February 17 (Item X)
    - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 March 23 (Item XI)
    - Baron von Wrangel to Herron (Item XI A)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell. Enclosing Baron von Wrangel's report, and giving his particulars, 1919 March 23 (Item XI B)
    - Herron to Mr. Henry Slobodin, 1919 March 28 (Item XII)
    - Herron to Colonel House. Enclosing following letter, 1919 March 28 (Item XII A)
    - Mr. Henry C. Slobodin to Herron, 1919 February 20 (Item XII B)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell. Enclosing Mr. Slobodin's appeal, for Mr. Balfour, 1919 March 29 (Item XIII)
    - Mr. N. Gay to Herron. Referring to unspecified memorandum, 1919 March 31 (Item XIV)
    - Herron to Mr. Gay. Acknowledging above memorandum, 1919 March 31 (Item XIV A)
    - Herron to President Wilson, 1919 April 2 (Item XV)
    - Appeal of "Free Christians" (Item XV A)
    - Given to Herron by Mr. Paul Birukoff for transmission. Impressions of his journey in Russia, 1919 April 2 (Item XVI)
    - Herron to The President. Enclosing above impressions, 1919 April 4 (Item XVII)
    - Preceding enclosure, English translation (Item XVII A)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell. Enclosing same, 1919 April 4 (Item XVII B)
    - Herron to Colonel House. Enclosing same, and also the situation in Hungary by Count Sigray and memorandum on Russia by Nicolas Gay, 1919 April 4 (Item XVIII)
    - Mr. Gay to Herron. Memorandum on Russia, 1919 April 2 (Item XVIII A)
    - Madame Olivier to Herron. Enclosing letter to The President, 1919 April 13 (Item XIX)
    - Madame Olivier to The President, 1919 March 24 (Item XIX A)
    - Herron to The President. Enclosing appeal from Professor Lammasch and one from Madame Olivier, 1919 April 15 (Item XX)
    - Dr. Charlotte Olivier to Herron. Giving thanks for help, 1919 April 18 (Item XXI)
    - Appeal to Herron. Siberian Mission in favor of Austro-Hungarian prisoners at Nikolsk Ussurisk, 1919 July (approximately) (Item XXII)
    - Mrs. E.P. Lawrence to Herron, 1920 February 2 (Item XXIII)
    - Same. American Y.M.C.A. ready to commence repatriation of prisoners, but Permit still required from Government; request for help, 1920 February 10 (Item XXIV)
    - Herron to Rev. Norman Thomas. Attitude towards Russia; Gorky as guest; Herron's pilgrimage in Palestine, etc., 1920 April 27 (Item XXV)
  - Volume X. Russia. Baron von Wrangel
    - Baron T. von Wrangel to Herron, 1919 February 15 (Item I)
    - Herron to Baron von Wrangel, 1919 February 16 (Item II)
    - Baron von Wrangel to Herron, undated (Item III)
    - Same, 1919 February 16 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Baron von Wrangel, 1919 March 8 (Item V)
    - Baron von Wrangel to Herron, 1919 March 15 (Item VI)
    - Same, 1919 May 14 (Item VII)
    - Herron to Baron von Wrangel, 1919 May 17 (Item VIII)
    - Baron von Wrangel to Herron, 1919 June 2 (Item IX)
    - Same, 1919 June 20 (Item X)
    - Same, 1919 June 24 (Item XI)
    - Same, 1919 September 29 (Item XII)
  - Volume X. Russia. Prinkipo
    - Dr. Serge Persky to Herron, 1919 February 5 (Item I)
    - Same, undated (Item II)
    - Report by Herron for State Department and British Foreign Office, 1919 February 6 (Item III)
    - Major Kruesi to Herron, 1919 February 11 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Mr. Hugh R. Wilson, 1919 February 12 (Item V)
    - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 February 13 (Item VI)
    - Major Walter E. Kruesi to Herron, 1919 February 21 (Item VII)
    - Brigadier General M. Churchill to Herron, 1919 February 27 (Item VIII)
    - Major Kruesi to Herron, 1919 March 11 (Item IX)
    - Mr. Frank L. Polk to Mr. Stokes, 1919 February 19 (Item IX A)
    - Mr. Polk to Major Kruesi, 1919 February 20 (Item IX B)
    - Major Kruesi to Herron, undated (Item X)
    - Senator G.M. Hitchcock to Lt. Smith, 1919 February 19 (Item X A)
    - Secretary E.B. Goddis to Lt. G.I. Smith, 1919 March 1 (Item X B)
    - Mr. F.S. Polk to Senator Hitchcock, 1919 February 27 (Item X C)
    - Herron to Major Kruesi, 1919 April 25 (Item XI)
    - Herron to "The New York Times," 1919 September 20 (Item XII)
    - Herron to "The New Republic," 1919 December 3 (Item XIII)
  - Volume X. Russia. Latvia (Lettonia)
    - Madame Anna Kenin to Herron, 1918 March 27 (Item I)
    - Same, 1918 April 16 (Item II)
    - Same, 1918 May 1 (Item III)
    - Same, 1918 May 8 (Item IV)
    - Same, 1918 May 22 (Item V)
    - Same, 1918 May 31 (Item VI)
    - Same, 1918 August 22 (Item VII)
    - Herron to Colonel House, 1919 March 19 (Item VIII)
    - Memorandum for Peace Conference (Item VIII A)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell, 1919 March 19 (Item VIII B)
    - Mr. A.J. Balfour to Mr. Meierovics, 1918 November 11 (Item VIII C)
    - Colonel House to Herron, 1919 March 20 (Item IX)
    - Madame Anna Kenin to Herron, 1919 June 16 (Item X)
    - Pamphlet, "Un Peuple Menacé" (Item XI)
  - Volume X. Russia. Ukraine
    - Dr. Eugen Lewicky to Herron, 1918 November 25 (Item I)
    - Herron to Lewicky, 1918 December 3 (Item II)
    - Dr. Lewicky to Herron, undated (Item III)
    - Various sent to Herron by A. Sévrinky, 1919 March 31 (Item IV to Document IV Q)
    - Herron to Mr. Sévrinky, 1919 April 3 (Item V)
    - Herron to Sir William Tyrrell, 1919 April 3 (Item VI)
    - Herron to The Hon. P.H. Stovall, 1919 April 6 (Item VII)
    - Dr. Edmond Privat to The President, 1919 April 5 (Item VII A)
    - Mr. Stovall to Herron, 1919 April 6 (Item VIII)
    - Herron to The President, 1919 April 7 (Item IX)
    - Herron to Mr. Stovall, 1919 April 8 (Item X)
    - Mr. Alexander Sévrinky to Herron, 1919 April 8 (Item XI)
    - Memorandum on the Directoire of Ukraine (Item XI A)
    - Mr. Stovall to Herron, 1919 April 9 (Item XII)
  - Volume X. Russia. Crimea
    - M. Djafer Seidamet to Herron, 1920 June 5 (Item I)
    - Memorandum for the League of Nations (Item I A)
    - Herron to Dr. Seidamet, 1920 June 19 (Item II)
    - Dr. Seidamet to Herron, 1920 June 21 (Item III)
    - Same, 1920 July 6 (Item IV)
    - Herron to Dr. Seidamet, 1920 July 7 (Item V)
    - Seidamet to Herron, 1920 July 19 (Item VI)
    - Dr. Seidamet to Herron, 1920 August 21 (Item VII)
    - Herron to Dr. Seidamet, 1920 August 22 (Item VIII)
    - Herron to His Excellency Comm. Orsini, 1920 August 24 (Item IX)
    - Commendatore Orsini to Herron, 1920 August 26 (Item X)